datingdirectaffinity.co.uk 2016-04-02

# Dating Direct Affinity: Find your perfect match with our affinity test

## Your privacy as a member

## 1. General Information

This privacy policy applies to the “Meetic”, “DatingDirectAffinity.com” and the services provided by Meetic Group (the "Services"). 

The terms ‘us’, ‘we’, ‘our’ refers to Meetic SAS, as defined under the applicable terms and conditions, and operating the Services. 

We uphold the strictest of standards with respect to protection of privacy and of personal data, and have made a notification to the French Data Protection Authority. Our technical teams do their utmost to ensure the safety of our sites. Internet security is a complex issue and no system can be considered 100% secure. Should a security breach occur we will endeavour to act as fast as possible to remedy the problem. To achieve a higher degree of protection of your personal data outside the scope of the Meetic Group’s control, we suggest you employ software devices for the protection of data transmission networks (such as updated antivirus systems, firewalls and antispam filters). 

Online payments are secured through the https protocol to assure that your data is encrypted upon being transmitted to the bank and processed by the bank. 

We will only collect your personal data, process or use it, if and insofar as this is necessary for the fulfilment and improvement of the Services, you have given your consent for this or have not objected to this, or this is required or permitted on the basis of law or other legislation. Typically, we will only collect this data from you, and we will tell you why we are doing this. If we do not collect this data directly from you, we will inform you that this is the case. The same is also valid for cookies, usage of which is described in our Cookie Policy. 

## 2. When and why do we gather information about you?

You are asked to supply information about you when you register with the Service, participate in a contest, respond to a survey, participate in a chat, acquire a subscription or send us a message via the contact page. Certain items of information are mandatory in order to gain access to Services. The mandatory aspect of each answer will be specified for each question, with an asterisk or otherwise. With regards to the Meetic search criteria form or the DatingDirectAffinity.com Test, the very nature of the Service requires a majority of answers in order to be effective. 

The data provided during your registration as well as the data you provide voluntarily within the framework of the profile (e.g. date of birth, nationality, ethnic origin, style of dress, education/degree, lifestyle, taste in music, film taste, pets, religion and income) is used to present you with matching profiles of members, as well as a personalised advert or special offers or services through the Services. 

We have the ability to retain your contact details should you input them on our website even if you do not complete your registration. 

If you are looking for the information we collect about your computer and or device through our use of cookies; then please see our Cookie Policy. 

## 3. What sort of information do we gather?

Personal data gathered by us can include your name, mailing and/or email address, fixed line and/or mobile telephone numbers, bank information, information about your physical appearance, photographs, voice recording, video, city and/or region, personal values, interests, and your use of the Services. 

Some information, comments or content (e.g. photographs, video, profile, lifestyle) that the Member optionally provides may possibly, under the responsibility and on the initiative of the Member concerned, reveal the ethnic origin of the Member, his/her nationality, religion and/or sexual orientation. By providing such optional information and checking the consent box displayed on the registration page, the Member concerned expressly consents to, and takes sole responsibility for, the processing of this mentioned "sensitive" data by us and our group companies (by which we mean us, any of our parent companies, and any subsidiaries of us or our parent company), and their service providers located within and outside of the European Union (herein, the "Meetic Group"). 

Furthermore, technical data is also gathered, such as the version of the Member's and any other visitor's web browser (Firefox, Chrome, Safari, Netscape, Internet Explorer, etc.), the operating system (Windows, Mac, Android, iOS, Windows Phone etc.) and the IP address of the system used, identification information of the computer or other device from which they are visiting. 

Finally, the Services operated by the Meetic Group may be using cookies or equivalent technologies, designed to store information used to identify the Member while he/she is browsing the Services and to understand the Member’s use of the Services, mainly in order to improve the Services and the browsing experience of the Member. The Member always has the option of preventing the use of cookies by modifying the options of his/her web browser. Additional information may be found in our dedicated Cookie Policy. 

## 4. Who has access to your information?

The information gathered about you when you subscribe to our Services is used to offer you our different Services. All precautions have been taken on our databases to archive your information in a secure environment. Only a small number of our employees have access to your information, which is only accessible in case of necessity. 

The information contained in your personal ad, your search criteria and your profile can be accessed on the Meetic Group websites, on the web, by email (newsletters), by mobile telephone or on our Audiotel Service (a value-added telephone Service). In addition, this information may be broadcasted directly by us via the Services or via our partners to persons interested in the Services, through newsletters or third-party websites, or by all other electronic (email, text messaging, etc.) or audiovisual (radio, television, etc.) communication tools, or by written press (newspapers, magazines, etc.), in order to increase your chances of meeting someone by promoting your person ads, search criteria and profile. 

Consequently, by providing his/her information through the Services, the Member expressly authorises the Meetic Group to reproduce and broadcast the information contained in his/her personal ad, search criteria or profile (personal data, description, images, videos, etc.) on all or part of the Services (on the Meetic Group websites and mobile application, on the Internet, by email, Audiotel) and/or in a general manner, on all distribution media, in particular audiovisual communication (press, radio, analogue television, digital television, cable or satellite) or electronic communication (email, Internet), throughout the entire world, including outside the European Union, and for the length of time established in these Terms of Use between the Member and us via the Services. 

Processing implemented by other entities of the Meetic Group is subject to their specific privacy policies. We may send you promotional offers from some of our partners, subject to your explicit and informed consent given during registration, unless you choose not to be contacted during your registration or unless you tell us that you have changed your mind at any moment thereafter. If you do not wish to receive any special offers from the Meetic Group or from our partner companies, let us know when you subscribe, or alternatively at any time by going to "My Account" or contacting us by mail. 

We may occasionally share general socio-demographic information that does not include names with selected partners to allow them to target their announcements (by age category, gender, etc.). In this case, we will not send these partners any information that would allow them to identify you. We may also share information related to your location with partners selected to allow them to target their announcements (by age category, gender, etc.) if the Member has activated this feature. 

For the purpose of applicable data protection legislation in the European Economic Area ("EEA"), the data controllers of the Services are the Meetic Group companies, including Meetic SAS (postal address: CS 10002 - 75320 PARIS cedex 09, France). 

By providing his/her information through the Services, the Member expressly authorises the Meetic Group company to which he/she has provided his/her information to transfer this information and the benefits of the above mentioned rights to the other companies of the Meetic Group, the service providers, and eventual successors of the relevant Meetic Group entity, located in or outside of the European Union, as applicable. 

## 5. Managing your information

Even if only registered Members can see the data, you should be aware that you are operating within a public space and therefore you are responsible for your own privacy. You are therefore able to actively influence what other Members find out about you. In order to do this, go to your profile and choose the option “this is only for me” or simply do not give the information. 

Furthermore there are different options so you can control who can see your profile, or whether other people can see that you are online. If you wish, you can also temporarily disable your profile. 

Finally, you can also actively control how many notifications and what information you would like to receive from us. Under "profile and account/settings", it is also possible to specify whether you would like to receive notifications when you receive a message, when a Member visits your profile, or whether you would like to receive any special offers from us. 

Each Member can access or request access to personal data concerning him/her in order to have it modified, deleted or to forbid any further use by us of it. Members can submit such requests for access by mailing their requests to the following address: Meetic SAS (postal address: CS 10002 - 75320 PARIS cedex 09, France, or by filling out the contact forms, and each Member shall carefully identify the sender's personal data. Similar rights granted by the other companies of the Meetic Group may be exercised through the "My account" section or by addressing directly to the relevant entity at its postal address. 

You can unsubscribe at any time from our personalised advertising under the setting "account / settings". You can also object to certain uses of your data, in particular its use for promotional purposes or for creating user profiles under pseudonyms for the purposes of advertising, through the means described above. However, please note that an integral part of our service is the creation of usage profiles, for example, to make you suitable partner proposals. 

If you no longer wish for the Meetic Group or its partners to reproduce or broadcast the information comprised in your personal ad, your search criteria, or your profile, you can terminate your account following the conditions detailed in the Article "Termination". Since this information is comprised of your personal ad, your search criteria and your profile, the termination will only take effect upon the next update or version of these communications (printed, press, audiovisual, or electronic) containing your personal ad, your search criteria and your profile information. 

## 6. Links to other websites 

This privacy policy does not apply to third-party websites and the Meetic Group companies are by no means liable for the privacy policy adopted by those websites. When Meetic Group companies provide links to other websites, they do not recommend the use of these websites and do not provide any guarantees regarding their content or the services and products supplied and sold by these websites. 

  * **Complete our free Affinity Questionnaire**
  * **View your compatible matches**
  * **Get in touch**
